Every group of female friends has the funny one,
في كل مجموعة من النساء توجد تلك الشخصية المضحكة ،
the one you go to when you need a good cry,
تلك التي تذهب إليها عند الحاجة للبكاء،
And this group was no different.
وهذا الفريق لم يكن مختلفاً .
Except that this was a community of groundbreaking women
إلا أن هذا المجتمع كان للنساء الرائدات
who came together --
اللواتي جئن معاً...
first to become teammates, then friends, and then family --
أولاً ليصبحن زملاء ثم أصدقاء ثم عائلة...
in the least likely of places:
في أقل الأماكن احتمالاً:
on the Special Operations battlefield.
في ساحة العمليات الخاصة .
This was a group of women whose friendship and valor was cemented
كانت هذه مجموعة من النساء التي توطدت صداقتهم
not only by what they had seen and done at the tip of the spear,
ليس فقط بما شهدوه أوالمخاطر الذي واجهوها،
but by the fact that they were there
لكن بحقيقة أنهم كانوا هناك
at a time when women -- officially, at least --
في وقت كنّ فيه النساء رسمياً --على الأقل--
remained banned from ground combat,
ما زلن ممنوعات من المعارك البرية ،
and America had no idea they existed.
ولم يكن لأمريكا فكرة عن وجودهنّ.
This story begins with Special Operations leaders,
تبدأ هذه القصة مع قادة العمليات الخاصة ،
some of the most tested men in the United States military, saying,
صرّح أحد أكثر الرجال خبرة في جيش الولايات المتحدة ،
"We need women to help us wage this war."
"نحن في حاجة للنساء لمساعدتنا على شن هذه الحرب" .
"America would never kill its way to the end of its wars," it argued.
"أمريكا لن تستسلم حتى تنهي حربها"
"Needed more knowledge and more understanding."
"تحتاج إلى المزيد من المعرفة والتفهم" .
And as everyone knows,
و بما أن الجميع كان يعلم أنه ،
if you want to understand what's happening in a community and in a home,
ان كنت بحاجة لفهم ما يحدث في مجتمع أوبلد ،
you talk to women,
عليك التحدث مع امرأة،
whether you're talking about Southern Afghanistan,
سواءاً كنت تتحدث عن جنوب أفغانستان ،
or Southern California.
أو جنوب كاليفورنيا.
But in this case, men could not talk to women,
ولكن في هذه الحالة، لا يمكن أن يتحدث الرجال إلى النساء،
because in a conservative and traditional society like Afghanistan,
لأنه في مجتمع تقليدي ومحافظ مثل أفغانستان،
that would cause grave offense.
هذا من شأنه أن يتسبب في مخالفة جسيمة.
So you needed women soldiers out there.
لذلك كنتم في حاجة لجنود نساء هناك.
That meant, at this time in the war, that the women who would be recruited
وهذا يعني، في هذا الوقت في الحرب، أن النساء اللاتي سيتم تعيينهن
to serve alongside Army Rangers and Navy SEALs,
للخدمة جنبا الى جنب مع الجيش و البحرية ،
would be seeing the kind of combat experienced by less than five percent
سيشهدن أنواع المعارك المجرّبة من قبل أقل من 5%
of the entire United States military.
من جيش الولايات المتحدة عامة.
Less than five percent.
أقل من 5% .
So the call went out.
لذلك بدأت الدعوة .
"Female soldiers: Become a part of history.
الجنديات النساء: أصبحن جزءاً من التاريخ.
Join Special Operations on the battlefield in Afghanistan."
التحقن بالعمليات الخاصة على أرض المعارك في أفغانستان .
This is in 2011.
كان هذا في 2011
And from Alabama to Alaska,
ومن ألاباما إلى ألاسكا ،
a group of women who had always wanted to do something that mattered
مجموعة من النساء اللواتي أردن دائماً القيام بشيء ذو معنى
alongside the best of the best,
جنبا الى جنب أفضل الأفضل ،
and to make a difference for their country,
وإحداث تغيير ببلادهم
answered that call to serve.
استجابوا لهذه الدعوة للخدمة.
And for them it was not about politics, it was about serving with purpose.
وبالنسبة لهم لم يكن ذلك بسبب السياسة بل كان الخدمة لسبب.
And so, the women who came to North Carolina
وهكذا، فإن النساء اللواتي جئن إلى كارولينا الشمالية
to compete for a spot on these teams
للمنافسة على مكان في هذه المجموعات
which would put women on the Special Operations front lines,
التي من شأنها أن تضع المرأة على خطوط جبهة العمليات الخاصة،
landed and found very quickly a community,
التحقن ووجدن بسرعة مجتمعاً ،
the likes of which they had never seen.
لم يوجد له مثيلاً.
Full of women who were as fierce and as fit as they were,
تسوده نساء شرسات وقويات أينما كُنّ ،
and as driven to make a difference.
ومستعدات لإحداث تغيير.
They didn't have to apologize for who they were,
لم تكنّ مضطرات للاعتذار عما كُنّ عليه،
and in fact, they could celebrate it.
وفي الحقيقة,كان يمكن أن يحتفلن به.
And what they found when they were there was that all of a sudden,
وما وجدوه عندما كانوا هناك كان مفاجئة ًللجميع،
there were lots of people like them.
كان هناك الكثير من الناس مثلهم.
As one of them said,
كما قال أحدهم،
"It was like you looked around and realized
"لقد كان ذلك كما لو أنك نظرت حولك و أدركت،
there was more than one giraffe at the zoo."
أنّه يوجد أكثر من زرافة واحدة في الحديقة."
Among this team of standouts was Cassie,
من ضمن هذا الفريق وُجدت امرأة تدعى كاسي،
a young woman who managed to be an ROTC cadet, a sorority sister
امرأة شابة استطاعت أن تكون طالبة بهيئة تدريب ضباط الاحتياط
and a Women's Studies minor, all in one person.
وعضوة بنادي الفتيات وطالبة بجامعة الدراسات النسائية كل هذا بشخصية واحدة.
Tristan, a West Point track star, who always ran and road marched
تريستان والتي ما كانت دائما تركض وتمشي
with no socks,
بدون جوارب,
and had shoes whose smell proved it.
وتمتلك أحذية ذات رائحة ندل على ذلك.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Amber, a Heidi look-alike, who had always wanted to be in the infantry,
أمبر التي تشبه هايدي والتي أرادت دائما أن تنظم إلى المشاة،
and when she found out that women couldn't be,
وعندما علمت أن النساء لا يمكنهم ذلك،
she decided to become an intel officer.
قرّرت أن تصبح ظابطة مخابرات.
She served in Bosnia,
وعملت في البوسنة،
and later helped the FBI to bust drug gangs in Pennsylvania.
و من ثم ساعدت مكتب التحقيقات الفدرالي في الإيقاع بعصابات المخدرات في بنسلفانيا.
And then there was Kate, who played high school football
أيضا كان هنالك كات، لاعبة كرة القدم
all four years,
لمدة 4 سنوات،
and actually wanted to drop out after the first,
والتي أرادت أن تتوقف عن اللعب في بادئ الأمر،
to go into the glee club,
لتلتحق بنادي الغناء،
but when boys told her that girls couldn't play football,
لكن عندما أخبرها الرجال أن النساء لا يمكنهم لعب كرة القدم ،
she decided to stay
قرّرت البقاء
for all the little girls who would come after her.
من أجل كل البنات القادمين من بعدها.
For them, biology had shaped part of their destiny,
بالنسبة لهم، لعبت البيولوجيا دوراً حاسما ً في قرار مصيرهم،
and put, as Cassie once said,
ووضعت، كما قالت كايسي،
"everything noble out of reach for girls."
"كل ماهو نبيل ليس في متناول البنات"
And yet, here was a chance to serve with the best of the best
لكن، كان هناك فرصة للعمل مع الأفضل
on a mission that mattered to their country,
على مُهمّة كانت ذات أهمية بالنسبة لبلادهم،
not despite the fact that they were female,
ليس بالرغم من كونهم نساءاً،
but because of it.
ولكن بسبب ذلك.
This team of women, in many ways, was like women everywhere.
كان هذا الفريق من النساء، في عديد الحالات، مثل كل النساء.
They wore makeup, and in fact,
يضعن مساحيق التجميل، وفي الحقيقة،
they would bond in the ladies' room over eyeliner and eye pencil.
كن يلتحقن بغرفة السيدات لاستعمال الآي لاينر والكحل .
They also wore body armor.
كما كانوا يرتدون الدراع الواقي.
They would put 50 pounds of weight on their backs,
كانوا يحملون 50 باونداً من الوزن على ظهرهم،
and board the helicopter for an operation,
ويستخدمون المروحيات للقيام بعملية ما،
and they would come back and watch a movie called "Bridesmaids."
ويرجعون لمشاهدة فيلم "Bridesmaids"
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
They even wore a thing called Spanx,
حتى أنهم قاموا بارتداء ما يسمى ب Spanx
because, as they found very quickly,
لأنهم، اكتشفوا بسرعة فائقة،
the uniforms made for men were big where they should be small,
أن البدلات المخصصة للرجال من الحجم الصغير كانت كبيرة ،
and small where they should be big.
ومن الحجم الكبير كانت صغيرة.
So Lane, an Iraq War veteran -- you see her here on my left --
اذن لاين، من المحاربين القدماء بالعراق-- ترون صورتها على يساري--
decided she was going to go on Amazon
قررت الذهاب إلى الأمازون
and order a pair of Spanx to her base,
وطلبت زوجاً من Spanx
so that her pants would fit better when she went out on mission each night.
لكي يكون السروال مناسبا لمقاسها في كل ليلة تخرج فيها في مهمة.
These women would get together over video conference
يمكن جمع كل هؤلاء عبر اجتماع مرئي
from all around Afghanistan from their various bases,
من جميع أنحاء افغانستان من مختلف قواعدهم،
and they would talk about what it was like
وسوف يتحدثون عن ما كان عليه الأمر
to be one of the only women doing what they were doing.
بأن تكوني من ضمن النساء الوحيدين اللاتي يقمن بذلك
They would swap jokes,
سوف يقومون بتبادل الطرائف،
they would talk about what was working, what wasn't,
سيتحدون عن ما سار على نحو جيد وما لم يسر على نحو جيد،
what they had learned to do well, what they needed to do better.
ما تعلموا القيام به جيداً وما يحتاجون تحسينه.
And they would talk about some of the lighter moments of being women
وسيتحدثون عن أهم اللحظات لكونك امرأة
out on the Special Operations front lines,
الخروج عن خطوط الجبهة للعمليات الخاصة،
including the Shewee,
بما في ذلك استعمال Shewee،
which was a tool that let you pee like a guy,
وهي أداة تُمكّنك من التبوّل مثل رجل،
although it's said to have had only a 40 percent accuracy rate out there.
من الرغم أنه تمّ إتقانها بنسبة 40 بالمائة فقط.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
These women lived in the "and."
هؤلاء النساء عشن فقط في "و".
They proved you could be fierce and you could be feminine.
وأثبتن أنه بإمكانك أن تكوني عنيفة وأنثوية.
You could wear mascara and body armor.
بإمكانك حط الماسكارا ولبس الدرع الواقي.
You could love CrossFit, and really like cross-stitch.
يمكنك أن تُحبّي التمارين الرياضية والتطريز أيضا.
You could love to climb out of helicopters and you could also love to bake cookies.
يمكنك أن تُحبي القفز من الهيلوكبتر وخبز الكعك أيضا
Women live in the and every single day,
النساء يعشن بطريقة "و" كل يوم،
and these women brought that to this mission as well.
واستعملن ذلك خلال مُهمتهنّ أيضا.
On this life and death battlefield they never forgot
في معركة الحياة والموت لم ينسوا
that being female may have brought them to the front lines,
أن تكون أنثى قد يكون سبب وجودهم بالخطوط الأمامية ،
but being a soldier is what would prove themselves there.
ولكن أن تكون جندية هو ما يُعزّز ذلك.
There was the night Amber went out on mission,
في ليلة ما خرجت أمبر في مُهمّة،
and in talking to the women of the house,
وعند محادثتها لصاحبة المنزل،
realized that there was a barricaded shooter lying in wait
لا حظت وجود قنّاص مُحصّن منتظراً
for the Afghan and American forces who were waiting to enter the home.
القوات الأفغانية والأمريكية لمُداهمة المنزل.
Another night it was Tristan who found out
وفي ليلة أخرى تيقنت تريستان
that there were pieces that make up explosives
لوجود متفجرات
all around the house in which they were standing,
حول المنزل الذي يقطنون فيه،
and that in fact, explosives lay all the way between there
وفي الحقيقة تلك المتفجرات كانت على مدى الطريق
and where they were about to head that night.
الرابط بين المنزل والمكان المُتسهدف في تلك الليلة.
There was the night another one of their teammates proved herself
وفي أحد الليالي أثبتت أحد الزميلات
to a decidedly skeptical team of SEALs,
جدارتها ختما بفريق قوات سيل البحريّة،
when she found the intel item they were looking for
عندما وجدت أحد رجال المخابرات الذي كانوا يبحثون عنه
wrapped up in a baby's wet diaper.
مُلتف بحفاظة رضيع مبتلة.
And there was the night that Isabel, another one of their teammates,
و في أحد الليالي إيزابيل وهي إحدى الزميلات
found the things that they were looking for,
وجدت مجموعة الأشياء التي كانوا يبحثون عنها
and received an Impact Award from the Rangers
ونالت جائزة "إمبكت" من قبل رجال الأمن
who said that without her,
والذين أكدوا بأنه لولاها
the things and the people they were looking for that night
ما كان سيتم إيجاد الأشياء
would never have been found.
والناس الذين كانوا يبحثون عنهم.
That night and so many others,
خلال تلك الليلة والليالي السابقة،
they went out to prove themselves, not only for one another,
هرع الكثير منهم لإثبات أنفسهم ليس بينهم فقط ،
but for everybody who would come after them.
بل لكل الآتين بعدهم.
And also for the men alongside whom they served.
ولكن للرجال الذين خدموهم أيضاً.
We talk a lot about how behind every great man is a good woman.
كثيراً ما يُقال وراء كل رجل عظيم امرأة.
And in this case,
وفي هذه الحالة،
next to these women stood men who wanted to see them succeed.
بجانب هؤلاء النسوة ساندهم رجال أرادوا أن يشهدوا نجاحهم.
The Army Ranger who trained them had served 12 deployments.
الجيش الذي دربهم كان قد خدم 12 انتشارا للجنود
And when they told him that he had to go train girls,
وعندما أخبروه بأنه سيُدرب النساء،
he had no idea what to expect.
لم تكن له أدنى فكرة عن ما سيجري.
But at the end of eight days with these women in the summer of 2011,
ولكن مع نهاية 8 أيام مع هؤلاء النسوة في صيف 2011،
he told his fellow Ranger, "We have just witnessed history.
أخبر زملاءه "لقد شهدنا لحضة تاريخية.
These may well be our own Tuskegee Airmen."
ربما سيكون هؤلاء توسكو آرمين الخاصين بنا."
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
At the heart of this team was the one person
وداخل هذا الفريق كان هناك الشخص الوحيد
who everyone called "the best of us."
والذي يناديه الجميع "الأفضل بيننا"
She was a petite blonde dynamo,
لقد كانت دينامو صغيرة الحجم شقراء،
who barely reached five-foot-three.
والتي بالكاد تبلغ ثلاثة خمسة أقدام.
And she was this wild mix of Martha Stewart,
ولقد كانت تشبه مارثا ستيوارت،
and what we know as G.I. Jane.
وعلى حد علمنا.
She was someone who loved to make dinner for her husband,
كانت امرأة تُحبّ إعداد العشاء لزوجها،
her Kent State ROTC sweetheart who pushed her to be her best,
وتحب مدرسة ضباط الصف التي شجعتها أن تكون الافضل ،
and to trust herself,
وأن تثق بنفسها،
and to test every limit she could.
وأن تواجه كل الحواجز.
She also loved to put 50 pounds of weight on her back and run for miles,
كما كانت تحب حمل 50 باوندا من الوزن على ظهرها والركض لأميال ،
and she loved to be a soldier.
وتُحب أن تكون عسكرية.
She was somebody who had a bread maker in her office in Kandahar,
لقد كانت تصنع الخبز في مكتبها في قندهار،
and would bake a batch of raisin bread, and then go to the gym
ويمكن أن تطهو كمية هائلة من الخبز بالزبيب ثم تذهب إلى قاعة الرياضة
and bust out 25 or 30 pull-ups from a dead hang.
وممارسة 25 إلى 30 تمرين سحب البار
She was the person who, if you needed an extra pair of boots
لقد كانت شخصا،ً اذا احتجت لحذاء
or a home-cooked dinner, would be on your speed dial.
أو عشاء، ستكون في الخدمة فورا.
Because she never, ever would talk to you
لأنها لن تُخبرك أبداً
about how good she was,
عن مدى طيبتها،
but let her character speak through action.
بل تصرفاتها تشهد على ذلك.
She was famous for taking the hard right over the easy wrong.
لقد كانت معروفة بدفاعها عن الحق ولو يعني ذلك بمفردها.
And she was also famous for walking up to a 15-foot rope,
كما عرفت بتسلقها الحبل لمسافة 15 قدماً
climbing it using only her arms,
باستعمال يديها فقط،
and then shuffling away and apologizing,
ومن ثم تنزل وتعتذر،
because she knew she was supposed to use both her arms and her legs,
لأنها تعرف أنه عليها استعمال كل من يديها ورجليها،
as the Rangers had trained them.
كما دربها المدرب.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Some of our heroes return home to tell their stories.
بعض أبطالنا عادوا إلى منازلهم ليخبرونا قصصهم.
And some of them don't.
فيما لم يعد البعض منهم.
And on October 22, 2011,
وفي 22 أكتوبر 2011،
First Lieutenant Ashley White was killed alongside two Rangers,
قُتل الملازم الأول آشلي وايت على يد الحارسين
Christopher Horns
كريستوفار هورنس
and Kristoffer Domeij.
وكريستوفر دوميج.
Her death threw this program built for the shadows
موتها حوّل هذا البرنامج الخفيّ
into a very public spotlight.
إلى برنامج عامّ.
Because after all,
لأنّه رغم كلّ هذا،
the ban on women in combat was still very much in place.
ما تزال المرأة ممنوعة من المشاركة في الحرب .
And at her funeral,
وخلال جنازتها،
the head of Army Special Operations came, and gave a public testimony
ألقى رئيس العمليات العسكرية الخاصة بيانا عامّاً
not just to the courage of Ashley White,
ليس اعترافا ًبشجاعة آشلي وايت،
but to all her team of sisters.
ولكن بكلّ زملائها في الفريق.
"Make no mistake about it," he said, "these women are warriors,
" لا تُخطؤوا،" "هؤلاء النسوة هم مُحاربون،
and they have written a new chapter in what it means to be a female
وقاموا بإضافة تاريخية لما يُمكن ان تكون عليه الأنثى
in the United States Army."
في معسكر الولايات المتحدة."
Ashley's mom is a teacher's aide and a school bus driver,
أم آشلي هي معلمة مساعدة وسائقة لحافلة المدرسة،
who bakes cookies on the side.
وصانعة لقوالب الحلوى.
She doesn't remember much about that overwhelming set of days,
لم تتذكر كثيرا تلك الأيام التي كانت مغمورة بالمشاعر
in which grief -- enormous grief --
التي تخللها حزن --حزن عميق--
mixed with pride.
ممزوجاً باحساس بالفخر.
But she does remember one moment.
ولكنها كانت تتذكر لحظة مميزة.
A stranger with a child in her hand came up to her
تقدمت امرأة غريبة ومعها طفلها نحوها
and she said, "Mrs. White,
وقالت "سيدة وايت،
I brought my daughter here today,
لقد جلبت ابنتي اليوم،
because I wanted her to know what a hero was.
لأنني أردتها ان تعرف ما معنى أن تكون بطلاً.
And I wanted her to know that heroes could be women, too."
وان الأبطال يمكن أن يكن نساء أيضا" .
It is time to celebrate all the unsung heroines
لقد حان الوقت للاحتفال بجميع البطلات المجهولات
who reach into their guts
الوصول إلى أعماقهم
and find the heart and the grit to keep going and to test every limit.
وإيجاد ذلك الحب والشجاعة للمضي قدماً وتجاوز كل حاجز.
This very unlikely band of sisters bound forever in life and afterward
تعهّدت هذه المجموعة من الأخوات بالخدمة إلى الأبد
did indeed become part of history,
وأصبحوا جزءاً من التاريخ،
and they paved the way for so many who would come after them,
ومهّدوا الطريق للنسوة الآتين بعدهم،
as much as they stood on the shoulders of those who had come before.
مثلما ما وجدوا هم طريق النسوة اللاتي سبقنهنّ.
These women showed that warriors come in all shapes and sizes.
كان هؤلاء النسوة مثالاً عن وجود محاربين بمختلف الأحجام والأشكال .
And women can be heroes, too.
كما أظهروا أن النساء يمكن أن يكونوا أبطالاً أيضا.
Thank you so much.
شكرا جزيلا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)